别跑啊  宝贝  你这是去哪
Come on, baby. Where you going?
好戏才刚刚开始
Hey, the party's just getting started.
救命  救救我
Help! Somebody help me!
贱人  过来
Bitch, come here.
放开我  你这个混蛋
Get off me, you son of a bitch!
你敢跑  看我怎么教训你
I'll teach you to run from me.
放开这个女孩
Leave the girl alone.
趁我没扁死你  赶快滚蛋吧
Why don't you get lost before I take you down?
老妈  准备好一品地球上最棒的煎蛋卷
Mother, prepare to feast on the finest omelet in the land...
再去做修女吧
before you join the convent.
不  我在为我莎士比亚戏剧课制作戏服
No, I am making costumes for my shakespeare class.
好了  你觉得怎么样
So... what do you think?
我似乎记起了
I seem to remember
要你给我制作一个"外星人"的万圣节服装
asking you to make me an E.T. Halloween costume
你却告诉我你不会针线活
and you told me you didn't know how to sew.
浮云而已  再说  你那会儿都32岁了
Details. Besides, you were 32 at the time.
重要的是  合适的戏服
The point is, proper wardrobe
可以帮助演员与台词相连
helps an actor connect to the words.
那我猜这身儿是麦克白夫人
So Lady Macbeth, I presume?
苔丝狄蒙娜[《奥赛罗》女主人公]
Desdemona.
是苔丝狄蒙娜啊
Oh, Desdemona.
是  我也是
Yeah, me, too.
不  你先挂
No, you hang up first.
不  你先
No, you.
这次该你了
It's your turn.
斯坦福大学听起来太棒了
Stanford sounds so amazing.
我都等不及一月的到来了
I can't wait for January.
-一月  -我那时候走
- January? -When I leave...
-去斯坦福上学  -什么
- for Stanford. - What?
阿丽克西斯申请了春季入学
Alexis applied for spring admission.
你记得的
You remember.
是  我只是觉得  你好久
Yeah, I just thought-- well, you haven't
都没提起过这件事了  所以我就想
talked about it for a long time, so I thought--
因为我每次提起  你脸上就那副表情
Because every time I did, I saw the look on your face.
就现在这个表情
That look right there.
不  亲爱的  斯坦福是个重大的决定
Oh, no, honey, it's just that Stanford is a big decision.
我是说  你应该好好考虑一下
I mean, you sh-- you should think it over.
我考虑过了  只有好处没坏处
I did, and there's no downside.
那是所好大学  阿什利在那里
It's a great university. Ashley is there.
到那时我也能修够提前毕业所需的学分了
I mean, I'll have enough credits to graduate early.
是  但是你不想
Yeah, but don't you wanna...
和朋友们一起
You know, finish off senior year...
上完最后一年吗  还有毕业舞会呢
with your friends, right, and prom?
你就不想去毕业舞会吗
Don't you want to go to prom?
是啊  阿什利刚给了我他的密码
Yeah. Uh, Ashley just gave me his password
这样我就能上网查看他的课程了
so I can go check out his classes online.
贝克特小姐  老爷
Lady Beckett, milord.
理查德  你哭了
Richard, are you crying?
才没  是洋葱
No, it's the onions.
好  我承认  不仅是洋葱  不全是
Okay, I'll admit, it wasn't just the onions. Not completely.
她再过几个月就要走了
I mean, she's gonna be gone in a few months.
我的小丫头
My little girl.
是  但她长大了  卡塞尔
Yeah, but she's growing up, Castle,
她要去一所很好的学校
And she's going to a great school.
这也是你希望的  对吗
That's what you want, isn't it?
是  我只是没准备好
Yes, I'm just not ready.
好吧  她准备好了  你们两个
Okay, well, she is, so you two are just
只是有点不太同步
not on the same page.
-那我应该怎么做  -放她走
- So what do I do? - Let her go.
相信我
Trust me,
如果你看得太紧  只会把她逼跑
if you hold on too tight, you'll just drive her away.
探长  探长  探长
Detective, detective, detective,
能透露一些关于这起凶杀案的信息吗
what can you tell us about this homicide?
无可奉告  抱歉
Uh, no comment. Excuse me.
为个小巷里的凶杀案  至于吗
For a murder in an alley, really?
黑斯廷警官  这是怎么了
Officer Hastings, what's this all about?
你自己看看吧  探长
You should see for yourself, Detective.
可不是嘛
Yeah, tell me about it.
所以说  他被
Uh, so he was...
从中间一分为二  从头
Split right down the middle, from the top of his head
一直到他的...
all the way down to his...
得了吧  这老兄都被一分为二了
Please. The guy was sliced in two.
要我说他早就不担心他的小老弟了
I'd say his unit is the least of his problems.
那是你不理解一个男人和他的
Then you do not understand the sacred bond
小老弟之间神圣的感情
between a man and his unit.
好了  那凶器是什么  断头台吗
Okay, so what was the murder weapon, guillotine?
一把剑
A sword.
剑尖断在身体里面了
The tip broke off in the body.
从血迹喷溅来看
Blood spatter indicates
凶手首先砍掉了被害人的手
that the killer first lopped off the victim's hand,
之后一剑纵劈
then took the big swing.
单刃刀  某种军刀吗
A single-edged blade, some kind of saber?
壮汉配剑  真有《权力的游戏》的范儿
Man, a sword. That is so "Game of Thrones."
埃斯波西托  看起来
Esposito, this looks like
这可能是仪式性的凶杀
it might have been a ritual killing,
给所有旁观者取像
so let's get photos of all the bystanders
-以防凶手回来查看  -这就去
- in case the killer came back. - On it.
另外  死者名叫泰勒·法瑞斯
Meanwhile, the vic's name is Tyler Faris.
因性侵犯被关入新新监狱  一年前刚放出来
He just got out of Sing Sing a year ago for sexual assault.
好  有目击者吗
Okay, we got any witnesses?
有  他当时正要侵犯的女孩
Yeah, the girl he was in the middle of assaulting,
名叫玛丽·马卡多
a Marie Marcado.
我昨晚在街角的马特酒吧遇见了他
I met him last night at Matt's bar around the corner.
他看起来挺不错
He seemed like a nice enough guy,
一直说他就要发大财了
Talking all big about his ship coming in.
总之  天晚了
Anyway... It got late.
我和他一起走了
I left with him.
但之后他就开始变得特别粗暴
But that's when he started getting all super aggressive.
我跑开后他抓住了我
I took off running. He caught me.
天知道他会对我做出什么  多亏了...
I mean, god knows what he would've done if--
多亏蛮王柯南及时出现
If Conan the barbarian hadn't shown up?
凶手长什么样
What did the killer look like?
太黑了  我没有看见他的脸
It was so dark, I didn't really get to see his face.
你没看见任何特征
You didn't catch anything--
种族  年龄  体重  身高
ethnicity, age, weight, height?
她对我们有所隐瞒
She's holding out on us.
蛮王柯南救了她的命
Well, Conan probably saved her life.
她才不想出卖他[也有害他被大巴碾过之意]
She doesn't want to throw him under the bus
或者是宾虚风格的二轮战车
or under a Ben-Hur-style chariot.
对  但她看见凶手了
Yeah, but she saw the killer.
就不担心自己的安全吗
Isn't she afraid for her life?
她可能知道他不会加害于她
She probably knows he wasn't after her.
恶劣惯犯被一分为二
A career felon smited in two?
这很有圣经旧约风范啊
That's very old testament.
有点"侠士"除恶的味道
This--this plays like a vigilante killing.
就像《紧急追捕令》里警探哈里手持配剑
Think Dirty Harry with a sword.
偏偏赶上法瑞斯犯罪的时候
Who just happens to be in the alley
出现在巷子里吗
when Faris is committing a felony?
时机有点可疑
That timing is a little suspicious.
凶手大概从酒吧就跟上了他
The killer probably followed him from the bar.
带把剑吗
With a sword?
确实是个问题
Touche.
我们去和他的家属谈谈吧
Let's talk to the next of kin.
法瑞斯太太  请你节哀顺变
Mrs. Faris, we're very sorry for your loss.
别担心
Don't sweat it.
你说什么
Pardon me?
这种事时有发生
These things can happen.
在这个世纪不会吧
Not in this century, they don't.
别理解错了
Don't get me wrong,
我从没想过我儿子会被人切成两半儿
I never expected my boy to end up in two hunks.
但我一直知道总有一天
But I always knew, one day,
他会落得这个下场  躺在停尸房里
he'd end up there, laying on a slab.
这又是为什么呢
And why is that?
因为他就是个一无是处的废物
Because Tyler was a no-good loser.
接二连三的闯祸犯错
He made one dumbass mistake after the next.
我懂了  据你所知他有没有
I see. Um, do you know if he was involved
卷入什么可能给他招来杀身之祸的事呢
in anything that might have gotten him killed?
我猜绝对是有
Oh, I certainly expect so.
他告诉一个人他马上要发财了
He told someone that his ship was coming in.
这是什么意思
What does that mean?
他总是马上要发财了
His ship was always coming in.
泰勒就是那样  满嘴跑火车
That was Tyler, always working an angle.
太太  我需要知道
Ma'am, um, I'll need the names
你儿子所有仇人的名字
0f all the enemies your son may have had.
那你得拿个大点的本了
You're gonna need a bigger pad.
盗窃  伤人  诈骗
Larceny, assault, fraud--
只要你想得出  他都干过
you name it, Tyler Faris has done it.
尽管如此  也不至于死得那么...惨
Still, nobody deserves ending up like... that.
那是他罪有应得
He got what was coming to him.
兄弟  那得由刑事司法系统做决断
Dude, that's for the criminal justice system to decide.
或许那把剑也是一种司法[正义]系统呢
Well, maybe a sword is a justice system.
你要是昆汀·塔伦蒂诺那还说得过去
Yeah, if you're Quentin Tarantino, maybe.
在过去的六个月里他多次打给
He made lots of calls to an untraceable burner phone
一个无法追踪的电话
in the past six months.
确实是人渣罪犯干的事
Behavior consistent with a criminal dirtbag.
听听这个
Check this out.
泰勒·法瑞斯在三天前在酒馆与人起冲突
Tyler Faris got into an altercation at a bodega three days ago.
等警察来的时候他已经跑了
He was gone by the time the cops showed up,
但是店主说他因为钱的事
but the shopkeeper says that he was fighting
和一个家伙打了起来
with some other guy over money.
-记下那家伙叫什么了吗  -记了
- Does the other guy have a name? - Yeah.
托尼·沃迪尼  这个家伙也有案底
Tony Valtini. This guy's got a record, too.
他当然有了
Damn right, he does.
我在缉毒组时就知道他
I remember Valtini from back in Narcotics.
这家伙可是黑帮的成员
The guy is totally mobbed up.
你猜怎么着
You know what else?
他的家族在泽西拥有一家肉类加工厂
His family owns this meatpacking plant out in Jersey.
托尼的外号就叫"屠夫托尼"
Tony's nickname-- "Tony the butcher."
我猜他以前绝对干过劈牛的活儿
I bet he split a few sides of beef in his day.
是  我是和法瑞斯吵过嘴
Yeah, I had words with Faris.
他曾在我的企业里为我干活
He used to work for me at Tony Valtini enterprises.
哪个部门  毒品销售
Which division, drug sales
还是赃物配送
or distribution of stolen property?
我是个合法的商人
I am a legitimate businessman.
法瑞斯干砸了  我就把他炒了
Faris sucked at his job, so I canned him.
他觉得我还欠他工资
He thought I owed him back pay.
我们像绅士一样解决了问题
We settled it like gentlemen.
你不相信我  就去问他
You don't believe me, go ask him.
那我们就得开个降神会了
We'd have to hold a seance.
他死了
He's dead?
这么说吧  泰勒·法瑞斯
Let's just say, Tyler Faris
已经不像过去那么完整了
is half the man he used to be.
分裂人
A man divided?
人格分裂
Split personality?
真的吗  没什么要说的吗
Really, nothing?
他被人用剑
He was cleaved in two
劈成两半了
with a sword.
剑
A sword?
更像是肉类加工厂用的那种长刀
Much like the long knives used at a meatpacking plant.
不是我  这和我一点关系也没有
Oh, hey, it wasn't me. I had nothing to do with it.
但我知道是谁干的
But I know who did.
是那个家伙
It was that guy...
是那个袭击我的疯"侠士"
That nut job vigilante who attacked me.
你从没报案说你遇袭
You never reported an attack.
因为我不想劳烦执法部门
I don't like to be a burden on law enforcement.
事情是这样的  一天晚上我刚离开我的仓库
Bottom line is, I'm leaving my warehouse one night...
那是两个礼拜前
two weeks ago.
这个拿着剑的家伙突然出现在我面前
All of a sudden, here comes this guy with a sword.
他指控我有犯罪行为
He accuses me of criminal conduct,
顺便提一句  那纯粹是扯淡
unjustly, by the way,
然后威胁说如果我不离开这里就要杀了我  然后
then he threatens to kill me if I don't leave town, and then...
你知道他之后做了什么吗
You know what he does then?
他之后做了什么
What does he do then?
他
He...
割伤了我  你看看
cuts me. Look at this.
看到了吗
You see that?
-看到那里的疤了吗  -看上去像个L
- See that scar there?  - Looks like an "L".
沃迪尼先生请你把裤子穿上好吗
Mr. Valtini, could you please put your pants back up?
这是他干的
He did that to me!
他用那把剑  割伤了我
He did that, with his sword, to me.
懂了吗
Okay?
这个人长得什么样子
What did this man look like?
我说了你也不会相信我的
You wouldn't even believe me if I told you. Okay?
但是
But...
我在仓库装了摄像头
I got cameras in my warehouse.
他逃跑的时候  被我拍到了
When he ran off, I caught him on video.
时间与沃迪尼称他
The time code lines up with the night
遇袭当晚的时间吻合
that Valtini said he was attacked.
而且根据急诊室的记录
And according to E.R. records,
他当晚的确曾入院  屁股上有刀伤
he was admitted that night, knife wounds to the buttocks.
那是正义之剑  老兄
The sword of justice, bro.
等一下  那是...
Wait, is that...
不会吧
No.
不可能
It can't be.
是的
It is.
我们的凶手是个超级英雄
Our killer is a superhero.
真的吗
Really?
一个超级英雄
A superhero?
是的  小巷的那位证人证实
Yeah, our witness from the alley confirms
她看到这个人杀了泰勒·法瑞斯
that she saw this man kill Tyler Faris.
那么她之前为什么不说
Well, why didn't she say that before?
她认为我们不会相信她
She didn't think that we'd believe her.
说实话  她没想错
And quite frankly, she's right.
一个蒙面"侠士"逍遥法外
A masked vigilante on the loose,
随处砍人
hacking people up?
告诉我你打算怎么将这个人绳之以法
Tell me what your plan is to apprehend this individual.
我们在寻找作案手法相同的凶杀案
We're, uh, we're looking for murders with the same M.O.,
同时也在调查泰勒·法瑞斯和托尼·沃迪尼
we're also checking into enemies that Tyler Faris
是否有共同的仇家
and Tony Valtini might have had in common,
还有  我们在查寻
and finally, we're trying to track down
那套套装和剑的出处
where that suit and sword came from.
和贝尔维尤医院联系一下
Reach out to Bellevue.
他们很可能接收过我们的嫌疑犯
They probably admitted our suspect before.
很显然  他不是有妄想症就是个疯子
He's clearly delusional or a psychotic.
是的  长官
Yes, sir.
随时向我报告进度  探长
Keep me apprised, detective.
是
Yes.
别在贝尔维尤上浪费时间了
Don't waste your time on Bellevue.
你在偷听
You were eavesdropping?
我有像超胆侠一般超于常人的听力
Can I help it if I have superhuman,
这能怪我吗
Daredevil-like hearing?
我们的凶手不是疯子
Our killer is not crazy.
他把一个人一劈为二了
He cut a man in two
而且他还穿着超级英雄的套装到处乱跑
and he's running around wearing a superhero suit.
我了解服装  这件市面上没有
I know costumes. That one is not commercial.
很可能是他自己设计的
He probably designed it himself,
说明了他具有正常人的行为能力
which means he's highly functional.
你知道我现在想要什么吗
You know what I would love right now?
我希望有人能给我一个
Is if somebody would come here and give me a theory
能帮我解决案子的理论
that would actually help me solve this case.
我有
I've got one.
所有超级英雄都有一个伪装身份  一个任务
Every superhero has a persona, a mission,
一个起源故事
an origin story.
了解他是什么样的英雄  是什么在驱使他
Learning who he is as a hero, what drives him,
可以帮助我们找到面具后的那个人
that will lead us to the man behind the mask.
卡塞尔  我们的凶手不是超级英雄
Castle, what good is comic book mythology
用漫画书里那套分析有个屁用
when our killer is not a superhero?
如果他是超级英雄呢
What if he is a superhero?
像这个在皇后区活动的一样
Like this one, who operates out of Queens.
来认识一下赤红侠
Meet... the Red Marune.
又赤又红  语义重复唉
Red Marune? Isn't that redundant?
不要担心  女士
Don't worry, ma'am.
赤红侠  保护众生  不偏不倚
Red Marune, protector of all, beholding to none.
先生  这显然不是你的钱包
Sir, this is clearly not your purse.
我命令你马上交出来
I demand that you unhand it.
女士  你没事吧
Ma'am, are--are you all right?
身手真矫健  令人赞叹
Wow. Impressive crime-fighting skills.
你说是基因突变还是多年的历练
What do you think, mutant powers or years of training?
谁都有掉链子的时候嘛
Yes, well, sometimes, the runner stumbles.
关键是  现实生活中
The point is, there is a subculture
确实存在这样一群非主流的超级英雄
of real-life superheroes that actually exists out there.
为了公众利益而战斗的一群人
People crusading for the public good.
是的  而且通常他们会被人海扁
Yes, and usually, they get their asses kicked,
就像这个人
just like this guy.
我认为我们的"侠士"就是其中之一
I think our vigilante is one of them.
卡塞尔  如果他为公众利益而战斗的话
Castle, if he's a crusader for the public good,
那他为什么要劈了泰勒·法瑞斯
then why did he partition Tyler Faris?
因为  在追寻正义的过程中
Ah, because tragically... his pursuit of justice
他不幸走上了黑暗的道路
has led him down the path of the dark side.
这样的宿命曾降临在很多超级英雄身上
That is a fate that has befallen many a hero.
谢谢
Cheers.
相信我
Trust me,
我在超级英雄这条线上已经有所突破
I am onto something with this superhero angle.
我的直觉蠢蠢欲动
My spidey senses are tingling.
他又怎么了
What's with him?
他的直觉什么蠢什么动
Something about spidey senses and tingling.
小巷里的照片
Photos from the alley?
我们可能找到一名嫌犯
We may have a suspect.
技术人员说这个人
Tech says that that guy
和蒙面侠的身高和体型都相符
matches the height and build of the guy in the suit.
不止如此  当他看到警察拍他照片的时候
Not only that, when he saw the cops taking his pictures,
他逃走了
he ran.
好的  让巡警拿着照片去排查
All right, have uniforms circulate his photo.
-我要知道他的名字  -好的
- I want to know his name. - All right.
要知道
You know,
卡塞尔说这个人是超级英雄说不定是对的
Castle might be right about this guy being a superhero.
我问了缉毒组的一个兄弟
I talked to a buddy of mine in narcotics.
他听说据谣传  道上有个人
He said he heard rumors about a guy on the streets
在驱赶毒贩子  还废掉他们的存货
rousting drug dealers and dumping their stashes--
是个拿着剑的蒙面人
a masked man with a sword.
没错  还是一把武士刀
Yes, it is a samurai sword.
所以我们在跟特色商店
So we're checking specialty stores
和武术用品供应商核实
and martial arts suppliers.
那套服装查得怎么样了
And what about the costume?
如卡塞尔所说
Not available in any stores,
没有商店有卖
just like Castle said.
说到服装
Speaking of costumes...
我知道凶手是谁了
I know who the killer is.
请看  我们蒙面"侠士"的照片
Behold--a photo of our masked vigilante
一同展示的是我收藏的漫威漫画
juxtaposed with issues from my own Marvel collection.
你有《终极复仇者》的首刊
You have "Avengers" Number 1?
不只如此  我还有很多
And there's more where that came from.
欢迎你随时借阅我的收藏品
You're welcome to peruse my issues anytime.
请注意凶手
Please note how the killer
从其他超级英雄的服装上
has drawn inspiration from costumes
汲取的灵感  例如
of other superheroes, for example,
它的配色让人想起蜘蛛侠
the color scheme evokes Spider-man,
带角的头盔  显然是向超胆侠致敬
the horned helmet--obviously an homage to Daredevil,
剑和剑鞘  取样自死侍
the sword and scabbard-- Deadpool,
高领  就像黑豹侠一样
a high collar, just like Black Panther.
那么这些人物的共同点是什么
Now what do these characters all have in common?
他们都是不存在的
They're make-believe?
都是受父亲或爱人的死所驱使
They're driven by the death of a father figure or loved one.
完全正确
Exactly.
我认为我们的凶手也有同样的背景故事
I believe that our killer shares a similar backstory,
所以这些人物的服装
which is why he's been inspired
给了他启发
by these characters' costumes.
不仅如此  除了服装之外
Furthermore, out of costumes,
这些超级英雄比较低调
these heroes tend to be unassuming,
所以我们应该把举止温和加到嫌疑人侧写里
so let's add mild-mannered to our profile.
卡塞尔先生
Mr. Castle,
你就是这样调查凶杀案的啊
so this is you working a homicide?
一个举止温和  双亲被人杀害的
A superhero who's mild-mannered,
超级英雄
and someone killed his parents?
他们不都是这样吗
Isn't that all of them?
这些能得出什么有用的结论呢
How can any of this produce even one useful conclusion?
请注意我们蒙面"侠士"
Let me direct your attention to the golden belt
戴的金色皮带
worn by our masked vigilante,
是根据《钢铁侠》在1963年发行的11期原版漫画
based on the golden belt worn by Iron Man
中所戴的金色皮带创作的
in only 11 original issues in 1963.
这又证明了什么呢
Which proves what, exactly?
我们的凶手收集漫画书
Our killer collected comic books,
意味着这个城市中有一个地方
which means there is one place in this city
他肯定会去
he would definitely go.
你知道吗  卡塞尔
You know, Castle,
你应该等到盖茨对你的态度缓和之后
You might want to tone down the theories
再大肆宣扬你的理论
until Gates warms up to you.
我准备通过解决这个案子
Oh, I plan to melt captain permafrost
来融化那座"万年冰山"
by solving this case.
好吧  祝你好运
Yeah, well, good luck with that one.
你闻到没有
You smell that...
散发着油墨的味道
Wafting scent of printed pages?
漫画世界在召唤
Comicadia beckons.
这是第一家漫画书商店
This place is the premier comic book shop.
是天主教徒的梵蒂冈
It's the Vatican to a Catholic.
是朝圣者的麦加  是待产鱼儿的上游...
It's Mecca to a pilgrim. It's upstream to a spawning--
这我知道  卡塞尔
I know, Castle.
我十四岁的时候在这买了第一套漫画
I bought my first comic here when I was 14.
罪恶之城之《为她杀戮》
Sin City, "A Dame to Kill For."
有品  好吧  等等
Hard-core! Okay, wait, wait, okay.
如果能让你变成漫画里的一个角色
If you could be any comic book character in the world,
你要变成谁
who would you be?
艾丽卡
Elektra.
一个冷酷的女刺客  隐藏着自己的情感
Ah, a ruthless assassin who hides from her emotions.
我选她或许是因为她的忍术超赞
No, maybe it's because she's got badass ninja skills.
换你选什么  钢铁侠  蜘蛛侠
What about you? Iron Man? Spider-man?
不对  等等  我知道了  烦人侠
No, wait. I know. Annoying Man.
是亿万富翁企业家布鲁斯·韦恩
Try billionaire industrialist Bruce Wayne,
即黑暗骑士  "蝙蝠侠"
A.K.A. The Dark Knight.
他有思想  玉树临风
He's brooding, he's handsome,
装备又酷到极点
and he has all the coolest toys.
你还真有研究啊
Digging deep on that one.
我跟你提过漫画世界
And did I mention what discerning taste
慧眼识珠的品位了吗
they have here at comicadia?
卡塞尔先生
Oh, Mr. Castle.
你...你是凯特·贝克特  对吗
A-and you're Kate Beckett, right?
麦克·胡佛  先生  我是你的超级粉丝
Mike Hoover. Sir, I am a huge fan.
见到你真是太荣幸了
It is such an honor to meet you.
幸会  幸会
Oh, the honor's mine.
我们刚刚拿到德里克·斯道姆漫画小说
We just got your Derrick Storm graphic novel.
那画面  那文字...
I mean, the art, the writing--
三个字  酷毙了
It is, in a word, awesome.
说说你最喜欢的是哪个段子
Tell me, what's your favorite part?
你不必回答那个问题
You don't have to answer that question.
他已经够自大的啦
His ego does not need any more feeding.
当然是德里克·斯道姆为逃脱俩坏蛋的魔掌
Definitely where Derrick Storm escapes from the two bad guys
-撞烂了出租车  -出租车
- by crashing the taxi cab. - Taxi cab.
对不起  贝克特探长
Oh. I'm sorry, Detective Beckett.
我不该透剧的
I should've said spoiler alert.
没关系  反正我也没打算读
Oh, no. That's okay. I won't be reading it.
当真  我们的名单上有你的名字啊
Really? I saw your name on our list.
你也预购了一本
You preordered a copy.
是吗
Did she now?
我只是稍微支持你一下而已
I was just being supportive.
不管怎样  我们来这不是为了那事
Anyway, we're not here about that.
我们有几个问题要问你
We need to ask you a few questions.
是的  有问题
Yes, we do.
你认识早期《钢铁侠》的收集者吗
I don't suppose you know of any collectors of early Iron Man.
抱歉  卡塞尔先生
I'm sorry, Mr. Castle.
我不能透露顾客信息
I-I can't share customer information.
麦克  你认识这个人吗
Mike, do you recognize this man?
不认识  没印象
Uh, no. He doesn't look familiar.
那么...
What about...
这个呢
This one?
是的  他我知道
Yeah, him I know.
-你知道  -是的
- You do? - Yeah.
-真的吗  -是啊
- Really? - Yeah.
这剑  这服装  是我们找的"侠士"
The sword, the suit-- that's our vigilante.
《孤胆仇侠》
Lone Vengeance,
这解释了他在托尼·沃迪尼背上刻的"L"
that explains the "L" he carved into Tony Valtini's backside,
但我怎么就从没看过《孤胆仇侠之剑》呢
but "Sword of Lone Vengeance," How come I've never seen this?
这个只能在网上阅读
Oh, it's online only.
它没那么主流  但还是有粉丝的
It's kind of fringe, but it has a following.
是个叫肖恩·埃尔特的家伙画的
A guy named Sean Elt writes it.
看来你对凶手的扮相
Looks like you put more thought
花的心思比他自己还多呢  卡塞尔
into the killer's costume than he did, Castle.
是从漫画上直接抄袭来的
It's a direct copy out of the comic book.
我见过那个
I've seen that before.
指节护盾吗  在哪
The knuckle plates, where?
犯罪现场的地上
On the ground at the crime scene.
我以为是颗扣子  原来是这东西
I thought it was a button, but this is it.
指节护盾从凶手的套装上脱落了
That's what it was. It fell off of his suit.
如果我们能找到那个
If we can find that,
如果它还在那  说不定能借此追查到凶手
if it's still there, it could lead us to the killer.
巡警们已经扩大排查范围了
Uniforms widened their canvass.
还是找不到任何认识这个神秘人的人
Still can't find anyone who knows our mystery man.
是啊  无论这家伙是谁  我尚未发现
Yeah, well, whoever he is, I can't connect him
他与任何刀剑有关联
to any swords either.
我祈祷我们能尽快找到他
I pray we nail this dude
省的我给那张名单上每家店打电话了
before I have to call every store on that list.
我以为你挺这家伙呢
Thought you were kind of rooting for this guy.
之前我以为他是个行侠仗义的好公民
That's when he was Joe citizen taking it to the bad guys.
结果他不过是一个穿紧身衣的二货
Now he's just some nimrod in a suit.
但他的精神还是值得称赞的啊
You gotta give him props for spirit, though, right?
难道你从没做过成为超级英雄的白日梦吗
I mean, haven't you ever wanted to be a superhero?
神出鬼没  飞檐走壁
Going out there, prowling the city,
行侠仗义
knocking some heads?
那就是我现在的工作  是的  我在听
I do that now. Yeah, I'm still here.
真的吗
You did?
什么时候
When?
我们马上到
I'll be right there.
两小时前杰克当铺售出了一把武士刀
Jake's pawnshop sold a samurai sword
给一个男人
to some guy two hours ago.
他们说他符合照片上那个人的外貌
They say he matches our photo of our mystery man.
也许他是想换掉那把
Maybe he's replacing the one
劈开泰勒·法瑞斯时断掉的剑
he broke off in Tyler Faris.
之前...就在这
It was... here.
我知道它在这儿
I know it was here.
也许被人捡走了吧
Well, maybe somebody picked it up.
或者那根本就是颗纽扣
Or maybe it was a button.
不  那是...
No, it's--
找到了
There it is.
这可不是纽扣
That is no button.
这是那服装上的一部分
That is a piece of his costume.
你是对的
You're right.
卡塞尔  我想这上面还残留了部分指纹
Castle, I think there's a partial print on it.
警察
Police!
站住
Stop!
真是酷毙了
How cool was that?!
哪里酷了  他就是凶手酷
Which part, that that was our murderer
还是凶手刚刚逃跑了比较酷
or that he just got away?
我得发个全境通告
I gotta call in an APB.
埃斯波西托  待会我再打给你
Espo, I gotta call you back.
等等  这个消息你一定喜欢
Wait. You're gonna want to hear this.
我们刚刚和凶手打了照面
Yeah, we just saw our suspect.
他从案发现场溜了
He fled the crime scene.
我知道在哪能找到他  因为我知道他是谁了
Yeah, and I know where to find him because I know who he is.
什么  怎么知道的
What? How?
今天他在当铺买了
Well, he bought a samurai sword
一把武士刀  而重点是
at a pawnshop today, and now get this--
他是用支票付的款
he paid for it with a check.
他的名字是...
His name is, uh,
查德·霍克尼
Chad Hockney.
他的照片与案发现场那个
His photo matches the mystery man
神秘人相匹配
from the crime scene.
他住在哪
What's his address?
纽约警局  别动
NYPD. Do not move a muscle.
除非你动起来比子弹还快
Unless you can move faster than a speeding bullet.
这家伙
This man...
他就是凶手吗
He's our killer?
但说句公道话
Well, to be fair, h--
他在暗巷里要牛逼很多...
He was a lot more imposing in a dark alley...
还带着把剑
with a sword.
是啊  他家离案发现场只有四个街区
Yeah, he lives four blocks away from the crime scene,
鉴证组此刻正在翻查他的公寓...
and CSU is going through his apartment right now to find...
在找能将他与凶案相连的证据
e-evidence to link him to the murder.
给我处理好了  探长
Tie this up in a bow, detective.
让他认罪
Get me a confession.
坐下吧  霍克尼先生
Take a seat, Mr. Hockney.
我想这是个天大的误会
Uh, look, this is just a big misunderstanding.
我是站在你们这一边的呀
I mean, I-I'm on your guys' side here.
我们这一边不会处决罪犯
Our side doesn't execute criminals.
对嘛  我也不会呀
See, yeah, neither do I.
除了昨晚的"好汉分两半"
Except for last night's episode of "Two half-men."
查德  我们有目击证人
We have a witness, Chad.
她见到你劈了泰勒·法瑞斯
She saw you kill Tyler Faris.
之后  你又飞蛾扑火一般
And then like a moth to a flame,
不顾一切地跑回案发现场
you were inexorably drawn back to the scene of the crime.
正是此时你意识到自己落下了套装的一部分
Which is when you realized you lost part of your suit.
所以又回去找护盾
So you came back to get it,
或者说  是从我们手里夺走了
or rather, take it from us.
这都是为了你父亲  对吗
This is all about your father, isn't it?
他的死驱使你复仇
You're driven by his death?
我爸爸在迈阿密
My father's in Miami.
我不知道你们在胡扯些什么
I-I don't know what you people are talking about.
那么你是说  你没有在暗巷里
So you're saying, you weren't in the alley
用剑敲我的手
slapping my hand with your sword,
也没有杀泰勒·法瑞斯
and you didn't kill Tyler Faris?
没有  我永远不会杀人的
No. I-I would never kill anyone.
孤胆仇侠也不会的
I mean, n-neither would Lone Vengeance.
你不是孤胆仇侠吗
Aren't you Lone Vengeance?
不是本尊
Not the real one.
本尊是漫画里的角色吗
The real one being the comic book character?
漫画里的角色不是真的
Comic book characters aren't real.
好吗
Okay?
我说的是那个扮成
I mean the guy who assumed the persona
漫画角色的人
of the comic book character.
-那是谁呢  -没人知道
- And who is that? - No one knows.
但他是超级英雄圈的传奇
But he is a legend in the Superhero Community.
我做赤红侠的时候就梦想能成为他
I dreamed of being him when I was Red Marune.
"保护众生  不偏不倚"
"Protector of all, beholding to none"?
你听说过我
You've heard of me?
我们看过那个抢包的视频
We saw the purse-snatching video.
是吗
Yeah...
那个啊
That.
那视频一上网
That hit the web
差不多就把赤红侠变成了个笑话
and pretty much turned Red Marune into a joke.
那段日子真是不堪回首
Those were dark days.
本来我已经打算退隐江湖
I was about ready to hang up my tights for good,
但后来又决定去向孤胆仇侠寻求意见
but then I decided to seek out Lone Vengeance's counsel.
他说了什么
What did he say?
让我离他远点儿
To stay the hell away from him.
但那  却坚定了我的信念
But that--that only steeled my resolve.
我做了这套服装  买了剑
I mean, I made this costume, I-I got a sword.
你们破门而入时  我正准备出门巡逻
I was about to go out on patrol when you guys busted in.
你是怎么找到他的
How do you find him?
我听说孤胆仇侠常常在南曼哈顿区出现
I-I heard that Lone Vengeance, uh, frequented lower Manhattan.
我夜夜在街上晃悠  希望能找到他
I-I roamed the streets night after night looking for him.
有天终于遇见他了
I finally ran into him, uh...
在比克曼街和剧院巷附近
Near Beekman and Theatre Alley.
我想让他收我为徒
I want to be his disciple.
或许
Maybe...
做他的搭档
his partner.
那是我的使命
It's--it's my destiny.
他不想要搭档
He doesn't want a partner.
你怎么知道
How do you know?
孤胆仇侠
Lone Vengeance.
"孤胆"
"Lone."
没法对他立案是什么意思
What do you mean, you can't make a case against him?
他的装束和凶手一样
He's wearing the same suit.
是的  可很显然穿一样装束的不只他一个人
Yeah, well, apparently, he's not the only one.
凶案发生当晚
Chad Hockney was in his apartment
查德·霍克尼正在自己家做那套衣服
making that suit the night of the murder.
事实上  当时邻居抱怨过
In fact, neighbors were complaining
缝纫机发出的噪音
about the noise from the sewing machine.
我告诉市长我们抓到凶手了
I told the mayor we had our man.
你不该告诉他的
Yeah, well, you shouldn't have done that.
或许我是不该
Perhaps what I shouldn't have done
相信你  探长
was place my faith in you, detective.
伙计们  摩托车查得怎么样了
Guys, where are we on the motorcycle?
正在查银色川崎摩托的注册登记
Checking registrations on silver Kawasakis.
我们还在比克曼街附近寻找
We're also canvassing around Beekman
其他见到过孤胆仇侠的人
for other sightings of Lone Vengeance.
申请法院令
Okay, let's put in a court order
调出所有下载过
for the names of all of the people
《孤胆仇侠》漫画的人的名单
who downloaded the Lone Vengeance comics.
凶手可能就在其中
One of them might be our murderer.
你初涉世事
To the untrained eye,
可能以为我老大不小还看漫画  但是...
this might look like a grown man reading comic books, but--
爸  我一直在想
I've been thinking about this, dad.
我觉得你该为我感到高兴
I think you should be happy for me.
我很高兴
I am.
我为你高兴  我只是会想念你  仅此而已
I am. I'm just gonna miss you, that's all.
我也是
Me, too.
可这是我想要的
But this is what I want.
过来  给我说说你的课程
Come. Tell me about your classes.
你一月上什么课
What will you be taking in January?
统计学入门
Uh, Intro to Statistics,
微观经济学理论
Microeconomic Theory,
伊斯兰中东经济学理论...
The Economic Theory of the Islamic Middle East--
阿什利才是学经济专业的啊  你...
Isn't Ashley an economics major? D--
难道说你选了跟他一样的课吗
Are you just taking his classes?
那样的话  我们就能多点时间在一起
That way, we can spend more time together.
有什么不妥吗
What's wrong with that?
引用蜘蛛侠名言
To quote Spider-Man,
"能力越大  责任越大"
"With great power comes great responsibility."
不是所有人都有机会
Not a lot of people get a chance
上这么好的学校
to go to a school like this.
你得考虑你自己的梦想
You need to think about your dreams
和你自己的需求
and what you want.
这就是我的需求
This is what I want.
这是阿什利的需求
This is what Ashley wants.
这都不是他的主意  是我的
This wasn't even his idea. It was mine.
阿丽克西斯  你不能满脑子都是阿什利
Well, this can't be all about Ashley, Alexis.
如果你们俩分手了怎么办  到时怎么办
I mean, what if you guys break up? What then?
我们不会分手的
We're not gonna break up.
你为什么要劝我放弃
Why are you trying to talk me outta this?
我没有  我...
I'm not. I'm...
我不想你草率地做决定
I'm just trying to stop you from making irrational choices.
为什么我做的每件事都要合情合理
Why does everything I do have to make sense?
难道我就不能随意而为一次吗
Why can't I just do what I want every once in a while?
你做事可从来都是那样
That's all you ever do.
你好
Hi.
我该先打电话来的
I should've-- I should've called.
瑜伽  卡塞尔  我在做瑜伽
Yoga, Castle. I was doing... yoga.
-快进来  -好
- Come on in. - Gotcha.
我有发现  会让你大跌眼镜
I found something that will shock and amaze you.
我下载了《孤胆仇侠》全集
I downloaded all of the "Sword of Lone Vengeances."
这可没让我大跌眼镜
That's not shocking or amazing.
听我说完
You didn't let me finish.
我一直在这些漫画中
I was looking for clues as to the killer's identity
寻找凶手身份的线索
in the comic books.
没有收获  但我找到了这个
I didn't find any, but check out what I did find.
看看这几幅图
Take a look at these panels.
一名暴徒走出他的仓库  孤胆仇侠出现
A hoodlum leaves his warehouse, uh, Lone Vengeance swoops in,
然后在他的右屁屁刻上了字母"L"
and then carves the letter "L" in his right cheek.
这让你想到了谁
Who does that remind you of?
屠夫托尼
Tony the Butcher.
我查了这本的出版日期
I checked the dates on the issue.
是在孤胆仇侠袭击他之后出版的
It came out after Lone Vengeance attacked him.
漫画重现了这次事件
These panels emulate that event.
唯一在场的人就是那位"侠士"
The only other person who was there was our vigilante.
-你是说...  -一定是这样
- So then you're saying that... - It has to be.
凶手就是这漫画的作者
Our killer is the writer of this comic book--
肖恩·埃尔特
Sean Elt.
好的  谢谢
Okay, thank you.
没肖恩·埃尔特这个人
Sean Elt doesn't exist.
这是个化名
His name is an alias.
我们作家管这个叫笔名[法语]
Or a nom de plume as we writers say.
但怎会有人选肖恩·埃尔特...
Though why anyone would choose "Sean Elt"...
等等
Wait a minute.
这是个乱序词
It's an anagram.
重新组合一下  就成了
Change the letters around, and you get...
斯坦·李  漫画大师
Stan Lee-- comic book genius.
相信我  他绝不是斯坦·李
Trust me, he is no Stan Lee.
连肖恩·埃尔特都不是
He's not even Sean Elt.
好的  谢谢  比尔  下次吧
Yeah, all right. Thanks, Bill. Maybe next time.
技术部门查不到他的真名
All right. So no help from tech on the real name.
孤胆仇侠网站是由肖恩·埃尔特一个人注册的
The Lone Vengeance web site is registered solely to Sean Elt.
不管是谁
Well, whoever he is,
被他写进漫画的不止屠夫托尼一个人
he put more than Tony the butcher in his comics.
我还发现另两件现实中发生的事件
I found two more real-life incidents
被写进了漫画情节
that wound up as storylines.
孤胆仇侠端掉了毒贩窝点
Lone Vengeance shook down a drug dealer,
这里他点着了一辆装满平板电视的卡车
And here, he set a truck full of flat screens on fire.
调出那两份警方报告
Okay, pull up the two police reports.
-看有什么共同点  -这就去
- Let's see if they have anything in common. - I'm on it.
谢了
Thanks.
事情说不通啊
Something doesn't add up.
不论在漫画中还是现实中
Lone Vengeance stamps out crime,
孤胆仇侠都在打击犯罪
both in the comics and in real life.
他很喜欢行侠仗义
He's into this vigilante-style ass kicking,
托尼那次还屁股刻字
or in Tony's case, ass carving,
可他从不杀人
but never murder.
那他为何突然要杀了泰勒·法瑞斯呢
So why would he suddenly kill Tyler Faris,
又为何要用这么残暴的方式呢
and why in such a brutal way?
《孤胆仇侠之剑: 这次是私人恩怨》
The "Sword of Lone Vengeance: This time it's personal"?
只可能是这样
That has to be it.
泰勒·法瑞斯一定认识肖恩·埃尔特
Tyler Faris must have known Sean Elt.
据我所知  他不认识
He didn't as best as I recall.
我从没听说过肖恩·埃尔特
I never heard of no Sean Elt.
你儿子跟漫画迷有接触吗
Did your son ever hang out with the comic book crowd?
他喜欢漫画吗
Was he into comics?
他只喜欢放荡学生妹那种
Just those slutty schoolgirl ones.
可最近  他完全迷上了...
Oh, but lately, he had gotten all into--
是什么来着
Oh, what was it? Uh...
《孤胆仇侠之剑》
Uh, "Sword of Lone Vengeance."
他提到过那漫画的作者吗
Did he ever mention the writer of that comic?
他最近有没有跟和以往不同的人来往
Was he hanging out with anyone out of the ordinary lately?
比如说斯文人
Somebody mild-mannered, perhaps?
事实上  几天前我看见
Actually, I saw him talking
他站在门廊和一个人说话
on the stoop to a guy a few days back.
他不太一样  穿着套装
He was different. Wore a suit.
面具斗篷那种吗
As in mask and cape?
西装革履那种
Jacket and tie.
我听到泰勒说
I overheard Tyler saying,
"我知道真相  我知道你的底细"
"I know the truth. I know who you really are."
能形容一下他的模样吗
Do you think you could describe him?
金发年轻人  还留着胡子
Uh, fair-haired, youngish, with a beard.
还别着那种塑料身份卡
Oh, and he wore one of them plastic I.D. cards--
一张绿色的
A-a green one.
金发  留胡子
Fair hair with a beard.
绿色的记者证
A green press badge.
罪案现场的那个记者
The reporter from the crime scene.
嫌犯是个叫保罗·惠特克的人
Our suspect is one Paul Whittaker--
曾是漫画家  现在为《纽约账报》
Former graphic artist who works the crime beat
罪案版写文章做报道
for the "New York Ledger."
他没上班也不在家
He's also a no-show at work and he's not at home, either.
我们对他做了全面通缉  还监视了他的信用卡
We put out an A.P.B. and we flagged his credit cards.
那就完全说得通了
Actually, that makes perfect sense.
作为一名罪案记者  保罗会在第一时间
As a crime reporter, Paul would see firsthand
看到不法之徒是如何扰乱治安的
how lawlessness would ravage a community.
这促使他无法单单报道罪案
Compelled to do more than just write about it,
而是带上面具  穿上紧身衣
he would don a mask and form-fitting tights
化身孤胆仇侠
to become Lone Vengeance.
可他惩奸除恶的计划遇到了阻挠
But his plan to purge the streets hit a snag
因为泰勒·法瑞斯威胁
when Tyler Faris threatened to reveal
要曝光他的真实身份
his secret identity,
使得孤胆仇侠别无他法
causing Lone Vengeance to cut him down
只好将他劈成两截
in a single, fearsome blow.
怎么了嘛
What?
徒弟成了大师
The student has become the master.
至少他努力了
Or at least, he tried.
事实上  对于一个真正的卡塞尔风理论来说
Actually, for a truly Castle-esque theory,
必须要考虑周全  密不透风
it has to be fully thought through.
别扯了
Since when?
我有考虑周全
I did think it through.
真的吗  那泰勒·法瑞斯是怎么知道
Really? Then how did Tyler Faris know
保罗·惠特克就是孤胆仇侠的
that Paul Whittaker was Lone Vengeance?
这个交给我
I've got that one.
我刚和《账报》编辑聊过
I just got off with the "Ledger."
原来罪案记者保罗·惠特克
Turns out that our reporter Paul Whittaker
有一部一次性手机
has a burner cell phone
用来和他的线人通话
that he uses to talk to confidential sources.
泰勒·法瑞斯拨打的正是这个号码
It's the same number that Tyler Faris made calls to.
就是说法瑞斯是消息提供者或是线人
So Faris was a source or a paid informant.
他们就是这么认识的
So that's how they knew each other.
也许法瑞斯向保罗提供
And so maybe Faris was tipping off Paul
街坊发生犯罪行动的情报
about crimes going down in the neighborhood
可出现在罪案现场的总是孤胆仇侠
but Lone Vengeance kept showing up instead.
正因为这样  法瑞斯发现
And that... is how Faris found out
孤胆仇侠就是保罗
that Lone Vengeance was actually Paul.
他和保罗对峙  威胁要曝光他的身份
He confronted Paul, threatened to expose him...
保罗·惠特克杀了他来隐瞒自己
So Paul Whittaker killed him to hide his identity
半吊子超级英雄的身份吗
as a half-assed superhero?
实际上  这非常符合超级英雄的心理
Actually, it's perfect superhero psychology.
一种共生关系
It's symbiosis.
孤胆仇侠是保罗·惠特克的一部分
See, Lone Vengeance is a part of Paul Whittaker.
正如阴阳  互为因果  互为依赖
Yin and Yang--one can't exist without the other.
封锁那片区域
Okay, seal off the area.
保罗·惠特克刚刚在第71街与第7街交汇的
Paul Whittaker just maxed out his ATM
自动提款机透支了
at 71st and 7th.
离漫画世界只有一个街区
That is one block away from Comicadia.
所有这些只要两千吗
2 grand for all this?
老兄  这是《绿巨人》第181期
Man, you got a "Hulk" 181 here.
光这一本就有...
That alone is worth, like--
赶紧给我钱
I just need the money...
要现金
I-in cash.
我这会儿有急事
Look, I'm in a bit of a hurry here
-所以...  -真的吗
- so, uh... - Really?
你急着要去哪  惠特克先生
Where are you off to, Mr. Whittaker?
还是应该叫你
Or should we say
孤胆仇侠
Lone Vengeance?
真的吗  凶手是个作家
Really? Our killer's a writer?
作家也可以是实干家啊
Well, writers can be men of action.
我可没见识过  卡塞尔先生
I've yet to see that, Mr. Castle.
他就像彼特·帕克一样  是个记者
So he's a journalist, like Peter Parker?
事实上  彼特·帕克是位新闻摄影师
Actually, Peter Parker was a news photographer.
而这位更像是克拉克·肯特
Yeah, our guy's a little more like, Clark Kent.
他是个斯文人  正如...
And he's mild-mannered, just like I...
我预料的一样
predicted.
探长
Detective,
我要给市长打电话
I'd like to call the Mayor,
告诉他我们已抓住凶手
let him know that we caught our killer.
最好让他认罪
Try to get a confession this time.
遵命  长官
Yes, sir.
我觉得她开始喜欢你了
I think she's warming up to you.
我们在搜查你的公寓  保罗
We're searching your apartment, Paul.
发现了这些画稿
We found this artwork there.
知道你就是《孤胆仇侠之剑》的作者
We know that you were behind "Sword of Lone Vengeance."
没有哪条法律禁止我画漫画吧
Well--well, there's no law against that, is there?
但你的所作所为可不仅是画漫画
Except you took it a lot farther than just making a comic book.
过不了多久
I mean, it's only a matter of time
我们就会找到你的行头和凶器
before we find the suit and the murder weapon.
孤胆仇侠代表着正义的力量
Lone Vengeance stands for all that is good and virtuous,
是独自与罪恶抗衡的勇士
an army of one at war against crime,
是无辜大众的守护者
a defender of the innocent.
但那只是我创造的人物形象
But that's just a-a character I created.
现实中没有这个人
It's not someone real.
根据记录  去年在一栋废弃的
According to this, you were mugged last year
居民楼外  你遭到抢劫
outside an abandoned tenement building?
这里是纽约
Well, it's--it's New York.
被抢劫很正常
People--people get mugged.
不过那个抢劫者挑错了对象
Only the mugger got the worst of it.
你不过缝了几针
You ended up with a few stitches.
抢劫者却重伤住院
The mugger ended up in the hospital.
当时警察认为你很不合作
And the cops say that you were "noncompliant."
在每个超级英雄的故事里
You know, there's a critical moment
都有一个关键时刻
in the arc of every superhero,
从那一刻起  英雄觉醒了
an awakening that transforms him,
并从此承担起命运赐予的使命
that drives him to embrace his destiny.
对于你  这次抢劫便是关键时刻
For you, the mugging was that moment.
孤胆仇侠在那时诞生了
That's when Lone Vengeance was born.
而《孤胆仇侠之剑》这部漫画
And then you used the "Sword of Lone Vengeance"
成为你的除暴日记
as your comic book diary.
我们知道你杀了泰勒·法瑞斯  保罗
We know you killed Tyler Faris, Paul.
普通人也好  超级英雄也好  都结束了
Your life is over, both of your lives.
监狱在等着你
You're going to prison.
你觉得若你未来的狱友们
What do you think those cons are gonna do
发现你曾穿着紧身衣以超级英雄自诩  会怎么对你
when they find out that you ran around in tights?
如果你帮我们省点时间
If you help us,
如果你主动认罪
if you confess,
我能保证你的安全
I will keep you safe.
让你待在隔离监狱中
I will get you placed in segregated housing.
这协议对你很有利  保罗
Now that is a good deal, Paul.
我是你的话就会接受
I would take it if I were you.
好吧
Okay.
那我说
Okay. Okay.
是我干的
It's me.
我就是孤胆仇侠
I'm Lone Vengeance.
泰勒·法瑞斯发现了吗
And Tyler Faris found out?
是的  他威胁要揭发我
Yeah. He--he threatened to expose me,
所以我杀了他
so I killed him.
我需要你写下来  保罗
I'm gonna need you to write that down, Paul.
你说孤胆仇侠是正义之士
You said Lone Vengeance stands for all that is good.
他是有准则的人
So he has a code.
而杀人这种事
So killing someone,
即便杀的是泰勒·法瑞斯
even someone like Tyler Faris,
也违背了这一准则
violated that code.
对于一个典型的超级英雄
In a typical superhero,
这会让他开始怀疑自己
that would trigger a crisis of faith.
你当时肯定很矛盾
You must have been conflicted.
你杀死泰勒·法瑞斯时  有何感觉
How did you feel when you killed Tyler Faris?
我感觉很糟
Well, I-I felt bad.
非常糟糕
I-I felt... really bad.
保罗  你在杀死泰勒后
Paul, why did you chop off Tyler's hand
为何砍下他的手
after you killed him?
我不知道
I don't know.
鬼使神差吧
I just--I just did.
可以让我写认罪书了吗
Can I--can I write my confession now?
还有问题吗
Is--is that okay?
你确定凶手不是他吗
Are you sure he didn't do it?
不是他  法瑞斯的手是死前砍断的
Yeah, Faris' hand was chopped off before he was killed.
保罗却不知道
Paul didn't know that.
那他为何要认罪
Then why did he confess?
因为保罗在保护真凶
Because Paul is protecting the real killer.
保罗是作者  孤胆仇侠是人物原型
Paul is the writer. Lone Vengeance is the subject.
这就是他们的关系
That's their relationship.
就像你和我一样
It's you and me all over again.
我是保罗  你是孤胆仇侠
But I'm Paul, and you're Lone Vengeance.
真的吗  卡塞尔  你这么看我吗
Really, Castle, is that how you see me,
挥着剑的杀手
like a sword-wielding killer?
要看你会不会穿性感的战斗服
Depends. Will you be scantily clad?
做你的白日梦吧
In your dreams.
不好意思打扰两位的漫画幻想之旅
Not to rain on your comic book fantasy,
但如果保罗不是孤胆仇侠
but if Paul is not Lone Vengeance,
那他的遇劫案也有了新疑点
it puts a whole new spin on his mugging.
确实如此  我猜抢劫者肯定不是保罗打的
That's right, it does. I bet Paul didn't beat up that mugger.
应该是孤胆仇侠干的
I bet that was Lone Vengeance.
他们大概是因此而相识
That's probably how they met.
等一下  保罗被打劫时
Wait a minute. That abandoned tenement building
所在的那个废弃居民楼  在哪里来着
where Paul was mugged, where is that?
在比克曼街和剧院巷交口附近
Near Beekman and Theatre alley.
那里也是查德·霍克尼
That's the same place
碰到孤胆仇侠的地方
where Chad Hockney found Lone Vengeance.
这要么是个巧合
So either that's a coincidence...
要么那就是他活动的地方
Or that's where he hangs out.
废弃的居民楼
An abandoned tenement building--
作超级英雄的秘密基地  再合适不过
perfect place for a superhero lair.
你确定是这里吗
You sure this is the place?
是的  电力公司说
Yeah. The power company said that
209室是唯一有电的房间
Unit 209's the only one with electricity.
有人从电线杆上拉的线
Somebody tied it up to a pole.
如果这也算秘密基地  我得说...
Okay, if this is a lair, can I just say...
真让人失望啊
disappointing?
制造神秘气氛的背景灯
I mean, where's the mood lighting,
装有50把武士刀的玻璃罩都在哪呢
the glass case with 50 samurai swords?
卡塞尔
Castle.
原来如此
All right.
原来是预算不够的秘密基地
It's a modest lair built on a budget.
很好奇他还藏了其他什么东西
Wonder what else he's got hidden around here.
贝克特  防火通道有个人
Beckett, got a guy on the fire escape
朝你那边去了
heading your way.
应该是他
I think it's him.
纽约警察  别动
NYPD. Do not move.
我是你的话  就老老实实的
I wouldn't do that if I were you.
楼下已被警察包围了
There are cops everywhere downstairs.
现在慢慢拿下面具
Now very slowly take off that mask.
黑斯廷警官
Officer Hastings?
这我可真没想到
I did not see that coming.
你能相信吗  孤胆仇侠
Can you believe it, Lone Vengeance,
挥剑杀手竟然是我们中的一员
sword-wielding killer, ends up being one of our own?
不好说  说不定她有苦衷
I don't know. Maybe she had her reasons.
什么叫"说不定她有苦衷"
"Maybe she had her reasons"?
你之前不是说"穿紧身衣的二货"
What happened to "nimrod in a suit"?
我之前又不知道是警察干的
Well, that's before I knew she was a cop.
鉴证组正在检查你的衣服  安
C.S.U.'s going over your suit, Ann.
检查是否有泰勒·法瑞斯的血迹
They're looking for Tyler Faris' blood.
他们是找不到的
They won't find any.
那是  你当然知道该如何善后
Yeah, well, you would know how to clean it up.
我一直很敬仰你  探长
I always admired you, detective.
你做警察的风格
The kind of cop that you are,
让我想去了解你
it made me want to get to know you.
你本来也能成为那样的警察
Well, you could've been that kind of a cop.
多次获奖  第一等的评估
Awards, first-rate evaluation...
你为何放弃了呢
Why'd you let it go?
我父亲在家附近开了家干洗店
My father owned a dry cleaners in the neighborhood.
被一个小混混
He got held up,
抢劫了
by some junkie, probably.
为了八十块把他打死
Shot dead over 80 bucks.
他下葬后的第二天  我向警校递交了申请
The day after I buried him, I applied to the academy.
而之后你决定亲自来执法
So then you decided to take the law into your own hands?
当警察还不够吗
Being a cop wasn't enough?
我爸爸被人杀了  做什么都是不够的
Someone killed my dad. Nothing will ever be enough.
但我现在做的事让我好过了很多
But doing what I do makes me feel better.
我们逮捕了安
We arrested Ann.
我觉得应该告诉你
I just thought you should know.
你...
You're...
大概在想我为何要认罪
probably wondering why I confessed, then.
因为你爱上她了
You're in love with her.
你做得过火了  安
You crossed the line, Ann.
不要假装我们有什么不同
Don't pretend like we're so different.
我们聊聊泰勒·法瑞斯吧
Let's talk about Tyler Faris.
-你失去了母亲  -这不是我们讨论的重点
- Didn't you lose your mom? - We're not here to discuss that.
你不是也一枪打死了那个凶手
Didn't you shoot the guy who killed her
而且就在这间分局里
right here in this precinct?
你挨的那一枪
The bullet that you took,
也跟她的案子有关不是吗
isn't that connected to her murder, too?
外面是这么传的
Because that's the rumor.
我跟你不一样
I am not like you.
我不会把一个大活人砍成两半
I didn't chop a man in half.
我也不干这种事
Neither did I.
就是你干的  你还让保罗·惠特克
Yes, you did, and you've got Paul Whittaker
深陷其中  难以自拔
so turned around over it,
他甚至试图替你顶罪
that he tried to confess to your murder.
保罗  他为什么要干这种傻事
Paul? why would he do that?
该死的  我叫他
Damn it. I...I told him
先出城一阵  等我把这事解决了再回来
to leave town until I got this sorted out.
你现在算是把这事解决了
Well, you got it sorted out now.
泰勒·法瑞斯不是我杀的
I did not kill Tyler Faris.
我看到他的尸体时  把早餐都吐出来了
I threw up my breakfast when I saw that body.
你当时就在小巷  安
You were in the alley with me, Ann.
你抢走了从你服装上掉下来的东西
You took that piece from your suit.
那不是我服装上掉下来的  我回去拿那件东西
It wasn't from my suit, and the only reason I wanted it
就是为了找出幕后真凶
was to figure out who's behind this.
-你不会指望我相信你的鬼话吧  -这是事实
- Do you actually expect me to believe you?  - It's true.
我在现场看到了那个护盾
I saw that disk at the crime scene.
我知道那不是我的
I knew it wasn't mine,
但是我还没来得及把它拿走就被派去排查了
but before I could get it, I got sent off to canvass.
所以我才回去拿
So I came back for it.
没错  是我从你那儿夺走的
And, yes, I took it from you.
那你是怎么处置它的呢
And what did you do with it?
让我一个在鉴证化验室工作的朋友提取指纹
I had a friend in the crime lab run it for prints.
上面有部分指纹
It came back with a partial,
但在刑事数据库里没能搜到
but it wasn't in the criminal database.
你不信我  就去问我朋友  东西还在他那儿
Look, if you don't believe me, ask him. He still has it.
你是说  是其他人假扮成孤胆仇侠
So somebody else dressed up as Lone Vengeance
并杀了死者吗
and killed our victim?
这是唯一的解释了
It's the only thing that makes sense.
这算什么解释啊
How does that make sense?
因为人不是我杀的
Because it wasn't me.
我在马特酒吧进行排查的时候查到点东西
I came across something when I canvassed Matt's bar
泰勒·法瑞斯当晚是从那儿出来的
where Tyler Faris came from.
泰勒·法瑞斯行动很有规律
He was a creature of habit.
他每晚都去那家酒吧喝酒
He drank there every night.
他总是在凌晨一点至两点间离开
He'd always leave between 1:00 and 2:00
每次都走酒吧的后门进入小巷
and take the back door to the alley,
而且通常都带走一个姑娘
usually with a girl.
所以你是说凶手知道
So you're saying that the killer knew
法瑞斯会出现在那个小巷里
Faris was gonna show up in that alley?
泰勒·法瑞斯不是她杀的
Well, she didn't kill Tyler Faris.
你怎么知道
How do you know?
我  我就是
I...I just...
我就是知道
I know.
要是她和查德·霍克尼都不是凶手
Well, if she didn't do it and Chad Hockney didn't do it,
就是有第三个人扮成孤胆仇侠
then we're looking at a third Lone Vengeance,
一个聪明的假扮者
A clever imposter.
好吧  假设我们的凶手
Okay, so, uh, let's suppose that our killer
确实是假扮者
is an imposter.
那就说明  他的目标就是泰勒·法瑞斯
That would mean that he targeted Tyler Faris
穿着特制服装
and wore a costume,
要么是为了防止别人认出他来
either to make sure that nobody could identify him...
要么是为确保别人能认出他来
Or to make sure he would be identified
然后把凶杀罪名嫁祸给孤胆仇侠
and frame Lone Vengeance for the murder.
而泰勒·法瑞斯则是最适合不过的刀下鬼
And Tyler Faris was the perfect victim.
是呀  他每天准时出现在漆黑的小巷里
Yeah, he shows up in a dark alley like clockwork,
还自带目击证人
even brings his own witness.
这样一来  我们要找的凶手可能是个
Okay, so then maybe our killer was a criminal
想除掉孤胆仇侠的罪犯
who wanted Lone Vengeance off the streets...
一个想报复孤胆仇侠
A criminal who wanted Vengeance
和泰勒·法瑞斯的罪犯
against Lone Vengeance and Tyler Faris...
一个了解泰勒  并且熟知他的习惯的人
Someone who knew Tyler and his habits...
一个有挥刀经验的人
Someone who had experience wielding a blade...
一个一开始把我们引向
Someone who pointed us to Lone Vengeance
孤胆仇侠的人
in the first place.
你们认为我杀了泰勒·法瑞斯
You think I killed Tyler Faris?
拜托  你在说梦话吧
Come on. You're dreaming.
我们知道你想除掉孤胆仇侠
We know you wanted Lone Vengeance off the streets.
他害你损失了不少钱
He was costing you money.
我们看过漫画
We read the comics.
孤胆仇侠害你损失毒贩
Lone Vengeance was shaking down your dealers,
放火烧你的卡车
burning your trucks.
所以当法瑞斯以为
So when Faris thought
自己悟出孤胆仇侠的真实身份时
that he figured out Lone Vengeance's true identity,
他知道你会下大手笔向他买这一信息
he knew you'd pay top dollar for it.
好吧  就算这是真的  当然事实并非如此
All right, even if this were true, which it's not,
我也没有杀泰勒的动机呀
I got no motive for murder.
孤胆仇侠这样骚扰你的手下
You had to be asking yourself all these times
你肯定无数次地问自己
Lone Vengeance was harassing your people,
他怎么得到情报的呢
how did he know where to go?
是谁在给他通风报信呢
Who was tipping him off?
肯定是你手下出了内鬼
I mean, it had to have been someone from the inside,
出了个居心叵测的人
someone with an ax to grind...
就比如说泰勒·法瑞斯
someone just like Tyler Faris.
所以你琢磨
So you figured,
何不来个一石二鸟呢
why not kill two birds with one stone?
除掉法瑞斯  然后再嫁祸给孤胆仇侠
Get rid of Faris and hang the murder on Lone Vengeance.
这就完了吗
And that's it?
你们就这点本事吗
I mean, that's all you got?
你们还敢自称是警察
You guys call yourselves cops?
真是丢人
You oughta be embarrassed.
问题是
Here's the problem --
你们没有证据
you got no proof.
我们还真有证据
Actually, we do.
这是从你的衣服上掉下来的
That's from your outfit.
我们在上面找到了你表兄厄奈斯托的部分指纹
We matched the partial print to your cousin Ernesto.
他是个裁缝
The tailor.
我听说他做定制衬衫的手艺不错
I've heard great things about his custom-made shirts.
同时他还供认曾为你做了一套
But he also confessed to making a Lone Vengeance outfit
孤胆仇侠的衣服
for you.
我要求请律师
I want a lawyer.
你的确需要个律师
And you will need one.
那些是你的随身物品
Those are your personal effects.
你最好检查一下  看看有没有少东西
You probably want to make sure everything is there.
谢谢  贝克特探长
Thanks, Detective Beckett.
安  你是个好警察
Ann, you're a good cop.
你身边也有关心你的人
And you've got somebody who cares about you.
别让你的过去左右你
Don't be so driven by the past
并因此丢了自己的未来
that you throw away your future.
多保重
Take care.
破了一起凶杀案
Well, a murder solved
还把一个臭名昭著的暴徒逮捕入狱了
and a notorious hoodlum off the streets for good --
我认为我们干的相当精彩啊
I call that a solid win.
我同意
I agree.
这全有赖于这支队伍的努力和敬业
All because of the hard work and dedication of this team.
谢谢你能这么说  警监
Thank you, captain. That means a lot.
我指的是警员
Of police officers.
这支警员队伍  卡塞尔先生
Team of police officers, Mr. Castle.
探长
Detective.
关于黑斯廷警官
About Officer Hastings...
你在小巷里命令她站住  她还是逃走了
she, uh, fled the alley when you ordered her to stop.
你能解释一下  你为什么不起诉她吗
Some reason you're not pressing any charges?
我
I, uh...
考虑到有这么多人穿那套服装到处跑
Think that given the number of folks wearing that costume,
我们也不能证明当时出现在小巷里的人就是她
we can't prove that it was her in the alley,
也无法证实出现在其他地方的也是她
or anywhere else for that matter.
没错  长官
Exactly, sir.
她是个有大好前途的警官
She's a promising officer.
也就是说  要是孤胆仇侠再次出现的话
That said, it'd be bad for all of us
咱们都得吃不了兜着走
if Lone Vengeance were to show up ever again.
我认为这种事不会再发生了  长官
I don't think that that will be a problem, sir.
你最好确保这一点
Well, let's make sure it isn't.
她这是大发善心吗
Either she just grew a heart...
我看是她担心万一媒体发现孤胆仇侠
Or she's worried about how it would look
是警务人员
if the press found out
我们不好收场
that Lone Vengeance was one of our own.
一位作家和他的缪斯
A writer and his muse...
携手对抗犯罪
fighting crime,
就跟咱俩似的
just like us.
明天见
Tomorrow?
好吧
Okay.
你好呀  母亲大人
Oh, hello, mother.
福斯塔夫[莎士比亚戏剧中的喜剧人物]
Ah, Falstaff.
不会吧
Really?
这是李尔王[莎士比亚著名悲剧作品的人物]
It's King Lear.
我还得改改
I have work to do.
干吗呢
Hey, What's up?
我在跟阿什利视频呢
Uh, skyping with Ashley.
不过现在聊完了
But we just finished.
你知道吗
You know...
你从小时候起
even when you were a little girl,
就是个严肃的人
you were a serious person.
我想我只是习惯了
I think I've just...
你一直都是
gotten used to you being...
很理智很成熟
sensible and mature,
甚至有时比我还要更理智和成熟
even more than me sometimes.
"有时"
Sometimes?
同意
Point taken.
问题是  阿丽克西斯
The thing is, Alexis,
我知道你还有不同的一面
I know there are other sides to you --
比如说  冲动的一面
impulsive sides,
浪漫的一面
romantic sides...
我不希望你刻意遏制你的多面性
and I don't want you to deny them.
你说得没错
You were right.
能力越大  责任越大
With great power does come great responsibility.
我一直很擅长做好自己应做的事
I've always been good at doing what I'm supposed to.
但是  但是上大学就是要做自己想做的事
But -- but college is about doing what you want,
追寻自己的梦想
you know, following your passion.
我决定自己选课
I'm picking my own classes.
我现在还没拿定主意呢
I don't know which ones yet,
但肯定不会是经济学
but, um, no economics.
你知道吗
And you know what?
即时你不能跟阿什利一块上课
Even if you're not in classes with Ashley,
你们也还是会有很多时间见面的
you still will see each other plenty.
我知道  如果我们住在一块就更能多见了
I know, especially if we move in together.